Selected Compositions of Frank H. Smith
Yale University Music Library
Selected Compositions of Frank H. Smith
1951-1963
Misc. Ms. 56
Yale University Music Library
0.5
(1 box)
Compositions by the American composer and flutist Frank H. Smith (1923-1958)
Smith, Frank H., 1923-1958
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was established in the Music Library of Yale University by Wencke Frimmin-Dahl Smith in 1963.
Arrangement
In 6 series as follows: I. Chamber Music. II. Choral Music. III. Flute Music. IV. Piano Music. V. Vocal Music. VI. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists primarily of photocopies of the holograph scores for 19 musical compositions by Frank H. Smith. In addition, the collection contains a small amount of biographical material, including academic records, programs, an obituary, and a photocopy of a letter from Henry Cowell regarding Frank H. Smith.
Biographical / Historical
Frank Hugh Smith, Jr. was born in San Diego, California on July 24, 1923. He served in the Air Force from 1942 to 1946. Smith was a versatile musician; his primary instrument was flute, but he also played the piano, conducted, and composed. After his discharge from the military, he went to France, where he studied at the Fontainebleau School and the Paris Conservatoire; his teachers included Nadia Boulanger and Marcel Moyse. In 1950, he married Wencke Frimmin-Dahl; they went on to have two children. In 1953, Smith received a bachelor's degree from the Yale School of Music. After further study in Europe, he returned to New Haven, earning a master's from Yale in 1956. At the time of his death on September 5, 1958, he was working on a doctorate at Boston University, and was about to become assistant director of the Yale Band.
Brass quartets (Trombones (2), trumpets (2)) -- Scores; Canons, fugues, etc. (Flutes (2)) -- Scores; Sonatas (Flute); Songs; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965
- Chamber Music, Series I
  - Short Suite for Brass Instruments, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    (2 B-flat trumpets, 2 trombones)
    (Photographic reproduction)
  - Two Canons for Two Flutes (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Three Settings for Percussion Ensemble, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - String Quartet No. 1, 1955
    - Score (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Score (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Parts (Box 1, Folder 6)
      (Photographic reproductions)
- Choral Music, Series II
  - Ave Regina Caelorum: Motet for five-part chorus of mixed voices, à capella (Box 1, Folder 7)
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1959) Boston, Mass.
  - Ego Ipse Consolabor Vos: Motet for four-part chorus of mixed voices, à capella (Box 1, Folder 7)
    E.C. Schirmer Music Co. (1963) Boston, Mass.
  - "He That Followeth Me": Four-part Anthem, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "In Thee, O Lord": Four-part Anthem, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Flute Music, Series III
  - Ondine: Fantasy for Solo Flute, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sonate for Solo Flute, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Suite for Flute and Piano, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Scores (2)
    (1 copy signed at end: "F.H.S.")
- Piano Music, Series IV
  - "Two Pieces for Betty-Ann", 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Intermediate Teaching Pieces for Piano
- Vocal Music, Series V
  - La Figlia Che Piange: Song for Contralto or Bass (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Korean Songs I: for Soprano Voice, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Scope and Contents
    "The Window-Glass And My Heart"
    "The Elephant"
    "The Butterfly And The Sea"
  - "Love", 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Prayer for Violence": A Holy Sonnet by John Donne, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Alto or Baritone Voice
  - Preludes: (T.S. Eliot) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Song": Poem by John Donne, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Soprano Voice
  - Three Songs, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous, Series VI
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Register to the collection.
    Smith's application to the Yale School of Music. -- 1951
    Smith's Yale registration form. -- 1952
    Complete transcript of Smith's grades at Yale. -- 1956
    Program for a concert including Smith's string quartet, Young Composers' Festival, Baltimore. -- 1956
    Letter from Henry Cowell to Luther Noss praising Smith's involvement in the Young Composers' Festival. -- 1956
    Program for a concert including Smith's Three Korean Songs, Yale. -- 1956
    Smith's obituary in the New Haven Register. -- 1958
    Letter from Smith's daughter, Hege Smith, reporting the death of her mother (Frank Smith's wife). -- 1973.